<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-10T04:45:35+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Wenxin Li</title><subtitle>Wenxin Li
</subtitle><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><entry><title type="html">Yunnan Dance</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/11/01/Yunnan-Dance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yunnan Dance" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/11/01/Yunnan-Dance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2024/11/01/Yunnan-Dance.html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>For piccolo (optional), 2 flutes, 2 oboes, 3 clarinets in Bb, bass clarinet in Bb, 2 bassoons (2nd optional), 2 alto saxophones, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, 3 trumpets in Bb, 2 horns in F,  3 trombones, euphonium, tuba, timpani, 4 percussion.</li>
  <li>Duration: 4 minutes 30 seconds</li>
  <li>Grade level: 3</li>
  <li>Commissioned by ASPIRE project led by Glen Adsit, the Hartt School.</li>
  <li>Program note: Yunnan Dance is inspired by the festive dances of the diverse ethnic groups in Yunnan Province, China. The music captures the vibrant energy, rich traditions, and celebratory spirit of these cultures through lively rhythms and colorful melodies. By blending the dynamic power of the wind ensemble with traditional influences, Yunnan Dance celebrates the rich heritage of Yunnan while offering a fresh and dynamic interpretation of its spirit.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><category term="orchestra" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For piccolo (optional), 2 flutes, 2 oboes, 3 clarinets in Bb, bass clarinet in Bb, 2 bassoons (2nd optional), 2 alto saxophones, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, 3 trumpets in Bb, 2 horns in F, 3 trombones, euphonium, tuba, timpani, 4 percussion. Duration: 4 minutes 30 seconds Grade level: 3 Commissioned by ASPIRE project led by Glen Adsit, the Hartt School. Program note: Yunnan Dance is inspired by the festive dances of the diverse ethnic groups in Yunnan Province, China. The music captures the vibrant energy, rich traditions, and celebratory spirit of these cultures through lively rhythms and colorful melodies. By blending the dynamic power of the wind ensemble with traditional influences, Yunnan Dance celebrates the rich heritage of Yunnan while offering a fresh and dynamic interpretation of its spirit.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ich Lebe Mein Leben in Wachsenden Ringen</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/01/Ich-Lebe-Mein-Leben-in-Wachsenden-Ringen.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ich Lebe Mein Leben in Wachsenden Ringen" /><published>2023-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/01/Ich%20Lebe%20Mein%20Leben%20in%20Wachsenden%20Ringen</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/01/Ich-Lebe-Mein-Leben-in-Wachsenden-Ringen.html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>Duration: 4 minutes 30 seconds</li>
  <li>Originally for soprano and piano; adapted for and premiered by Anne Amen.</li>
  <li>Program note: 
I live my life in growing circles
which ring out over the things around me.
Perhaps I’ll never finish the last,
but that’s what I’m going to try.</li>
</ul>

<p>I’m circling around God, around the ancient tower,
and I’ve been circling for thousands of years;
and I still don’t know: am I a falcon, a storm
or a great song.</p>

<div><div class="extensions extensions--video">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ECRJJ3jM_vo?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><category term="chamber" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Duration: 4 minutes 30 seconds Originally for soprano and piano; adapted for and premiered by Anne Amen. Program note: I live my life in growing circles which ring out over the things around me. Perhaps I’ll never finish the last, but that’s what I’m going to try. I’m circling around God, around the ancient tower, and I’ve been circling for thousands of years; and I still don’t know: am I a falcon, a storm or a great song.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wu</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/wu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wu" /><published>2023-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/Wu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/wu/"><![CDATA[<ul class="piece-info-list">
  <li>
    Duration: 7 minutes 30 seconds
  </li>
  <li>
    Written for and premiered at SPLICE Festival V, Berklee College of Music, 2023.
  </li>
  <li>
    Program note: 
    <div class="program-notes">
      Wu is a live electronics piece working with motion detection in Max/MSP. It tracks the performer’s body movements with a camera and translates those movements to control commands for playing and mixing pre-recorded sounds. Wu (舞) in Chinese means dance. Normally dance comes after music. However, in this piece, dance creates the music.
    </div>
  </li>
</ul>

<div><div class="extensions extensions--video">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XW5EXNSzEBM?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>
</div>

<p><img src="/assets/images/Wu Max Patch.png" alt="Max Patch" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><category term="electronic" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Duration: 7 minutes 30 seconds Written for and premiered at SPLICE Festival V, Berklee College of Music, 2023. Program note: Wu is a live electronics piece working with motion detection in Max/MSP. It tracks the performer’s body movements with a camera and translates those movements to control commands for playing and mixing pre-recorded sounds. Wu (舞) in Chinese means dance. Normally dance comes after music. However, in this piece, dance creates the music.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kong Shan Xin Yu (Rain in the Mountains)</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/04/15/Rain-in-the-Mountains.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kong Shan Xin Yu (Rain in the Mountains)" /><published>2023-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/04/15/Rain-in-the-Mountains</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/04/15/Rain-in-the-Mountains.html"><![CDATA[<div><iframe class="extensions extensions--audio" width="100%" height="166" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1538027740&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay">
</iframe></div>

<p>Setting of a Chinese poem from the Tang dynasty, commissioned and performed by Heritage Chorale.</p>]]></content><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><category term="choir" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Setting of a Chinese poem from the Tang dynasty, commissioned and performed by Heritage Chorale.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">from afar</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/01/From-Afar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="from afar" /><published>2022-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/01/From-Afar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/11/01/From-Afar.html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>2222, 4221, timpani+3 perc, harp, strings</li>
  <li>Duration: 16 minutes (I. Dung Chen 6’, II. Luo Gu 5’, III. Gu Qin 5’)</li>
  <li>1st movement read by Aspen Conducting Academy, Joseph Carlomaglo, conductor 
2nd movement read by Indiana University Concert Orchestra, Jeffery Meyer, conductor.</li>
  <li>Awards and festival appearances: 
American Composers Orchestra EarShot Readings, Indiana University, 2025
Aspen Music Festival and School, 2021</li>
  <li>Program note: 
from afar, a composition in three movements scored for full orchestra, draws inspiration from the Tibetan horn called the dungchen, the Chinese percussion ensemble luogu, and the plucked seven-string Chinese zither guqin. Each movement explores the unique timbres, techniques, and cultural significance of these traditional instruments within a contemporary orchestral framework.
The first movement captures the deep, resonant tones and harmonic complexity of the dungchen, evoking its ceremonial majesty through layered textures and dynamic swells. The second movement channels the vibrant energy of luogu, with its driving rhythms and intricate interplay, reimagining the percussion ensemble’s energy through orchestral forces. The final movement reflects the introspective spirit of the guqin, embracing free phrasing, pentatonic scales, and delicate ornamentation to create a meditative soundscape.
The title, from afar, speaks to both physical and cultural distances, honoring the rich traditions of these instruments while reimagining their essence in a contemporary orchestral language. This work invites listeners to embark on a journey that bridges past and present, exploring unfamiliar yet profoundly evocative sonic landscapes.</li>
</ul>

<div><iframe class="extensions extensions--audio" width="100%" height="166" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1374541549&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay">
</iframe></div>
<div><iframe class="extensions extensions--audio" width="100%" height="166" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/2085849909&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay">
</iframe></div>]]></content><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><category term="orchestra" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[2222, 4221, timpani+3 perc, harp, strings Duration: 16 minutes (I. Dung Chen 6’, II. Luo Gu 5’, III. Gu Qin 5’) 1st movement read by Aspen Conducting Academy, Joseph Carlomaglo, conductor 2nd movement read by Indiana University Concert Orchestra, Jeffery Meyer, conductor. Awards and festival appearances: American Composers Orchestra EarShot Readings, Indiana University, 2025 Aspen Music Festival and School, 2021 Program note: from afar, a composition in three movements scored for full orchestra, draws inspiration from the Tibetan horn called the dungchen, the Chinese percussion ensemble luogu, and the plucked seven-string Chinese zither guqin. Each movement explores the unique timbres, techniques, and cultural significance of these traditional instruments within a contemporary orchestral framework. The first movement captures the deep, resonant tones and harmonic complexity of the dungchen, evoking its ceremonial majesty through layered textures and dynamic swells. The second movement channels the vibrant energy of luogu, with its driving rhythms and intricate interplay, reimagining the percussion ensemble’s energy through orchestral forces. The final movement reflects the introspective spirit of the guqin, embracing free phrasing, pentatonic scales, and delicate ornamentation to create a meditative soundscape. The title, from afar, speaks to both physical and cultural distances, honoring the rich traditions of these instruments while reimagining their essence in a contemporary orchestral language. This work invites listeners to embark on a journey that bridges past and present, exploring unfamiliar yet profoundly evocative sonic landscapes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">For Dreams Will Be Cold</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/01/31/For-Dreams-Will-Be-Cold.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="For Dreams Will Be Cold" /><published>2022-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/01/31/For-Dreams-Will-Be-Cold</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2022/01/31/For-Dreams-Will-Be-Cold.html"><![CDATA[<div><div class="extensions extensions--video">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f9YyfS3NZGk?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>
</div>

<p>My then fiancé (now husband) and I had been in a long-distance relationship for nearly two years. The most difficult moments were not when we are apart, but when I had to watch them drive away after visits. The shortlived happiness of yesterday fresh in my mind, doubled the aching of the long and lonely anticipation of the coming days. In these times, I was reminded of the Chinese poem by Li Shutong saying “dreams will be cold after tonight’s farewell (今宵别梦寒).”</p>]]></content><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><category term="chamber" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My then fiancé (now husband) and I had been in a long-distance relationship for nearly two years. The most difficult moments were not when we are apart, but when I had to watch them drive away after visits. The shortlived happiness of yesterday fresh in my mind, doubled the aching of the long and lonely anticipation of the coming days. In these times, I was reminded of the Chinese poem by Li Shutong saying “dreams will be cold after tonight’s farewell (今宵别梦寒).”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When the Moon Came Up</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/11/01/When-the-Moon-Came-Up-for-soprano.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When the Moon Came Up" /><published>2021-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/11/01/When%20the%20Moon%20Came%20Up%20for%20soprano</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/11/01/When-the-Moon-Came-Up-for-soprano.html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>Duration: 6 minutes</li>
  <li>Written for and premiered by Ensemble Dal Niente</li>
  <li>Program note: When the Moon Came Up is an ensemble piece built around two contrasting themes. One is fragmented and cluttered, while the other is lyrical and melodic. These themes constantly evolve, contrasting and intertwining throughout the piece. The lyrics are composed of fragmented syllables, words, and phrases from the Chinese folk song 小河淌水 (Xiao He Tang Shui). The title, When the Moon Came Up, is drawn from the song’s opening phrase, “yue liang chu lai,” which means “the moon comes up.”</li>
</ul>

<div><div class="extensions extensions--video">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L7b_uRV07Dg?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><category term="chamber" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Duration: 6 minutes Written for and premiered by Ensemble Dal Niente Program note: When the Moon Came Up is an ensemble piece built around two contrasting themes. One is fragmented and cluttered, while the other is lyrical and melodic. These themes constantly evolve, contrasting and intertwining throughout the piece. The lyrics are composed of fragmented syllables, words, and phrases from the Chinese folk song 小河淌水 (Xiao He Tang Shui). The title, When the Moon Came Up, is drawn from the song’s opening phrase, “yue liang chu lai,” which means “the moon comes up.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wind Whistle</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/11/01/Wind-Whistle.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wind Whistle" /><published>2021-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/11/01/Wind%20Whistle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2021/11/01/Wind-Whistle.html"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>Duration: 6 minutes</li>
  <li>Written for and Premiered by H2 Quartet</li>
  <li>Awards and festival appearances: 
First Prize, Chengdu Jiezi Saxophone Composition Contest, 2023
RED NOTE New Music Festival, Illinois State University, 2022</li>
  <li>Program note: Wind Whistle focuses on the conflict and intertwinement between two characters: one is active, fast and restless, while the other is long, sustained and drowning. Both ideas are presented in the very beginning of the piece, and developed throughout in various formats, including multiphonics, slap tonguing, timbre trill, etc. The piece evokes the sensation of a winter wind weaving through cracks in a window, capturing both the sharpness of the breeze and the underlying calm.</li>
</ul>

<div><div class="extensions extensions--video">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wX62G13sVV4?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><category term="chamber" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Duration: 6 minutes Written for and Premiered by H2 Quartet Awards and festival appearances: First Prize, Chengdu Jiezi Saxophone Composition Contest, 2023 RED NOTE New Music Festival, Illinois State University, 2022 Program note: Wind Whistle focuses on the conflict and intertwinement between two characters: one is active, fast and restless, while the other is long, sustained and drowning. Both ideas are presented in the very beginning of the piece, and developed throughout in various formats, including multiphonics, slap tonguing, timbre trill, etc. The piece evokes the sensation of a winter wind weaving through cracks in a window, capturing both the sharpness of the breeze and the underlying calm.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Shadow of Sky</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/shadow-of-sky/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shadow of Sky" /><published>2019-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/Shadow-of-Sky</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/shadow-of-sky/"><![CDATA[<ul class="piece-info-list">
  <li>
    Duration: 8 minutes
  </li>
  <li>
    Written for and premiered by David Mercedes
  </li>
  <li>
    Awards and festival appearances: Midwest Composers Symposium, Indiana University, 2019
  </li>
  <li>
    Program note: 
    <div class="program-notes">
      <p>Shadow of Sky is inspired by the ancient Chinese song Sky-shading Apricot Blossoms (杏花天影), composed by Jiang Kui in 1187 AD. The piece is built on the first four notes of the original melody, which form a quasi-symmetrical structure. This symmetry serves as a foundation for the piece and recurs throughout its pitch content, rhythmic patterns, and overall form.</p>
      <p>The tuba, used here as both a melodic and textural voice, employs extended techniques such as exhaling, singing, whispering, and whistling through the instrument to evoke the fragility and depth of an ancient song. These acoustic gestures are captured and transformed in real time through a custom Max/MSP patch, which processes the live input using effects such as granulation, delay, reverb, spatialization, and harmonic layering.</p>
      <p>Triggering and modulation of the effects are controlled via keyboard input, allowing the performer to interact with and shape the electronics throughout the piece. This integration of live processing and acoustic expression creates a fluid, immersive sound world where tradition and technology intertwine.</p>
    </div>
  </li>
</ul>

<div><div class="extensions extensions--video">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5W5WeKnPSFo?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>
</div>

<p><img src="/assets/images/Shadow of Sky Max Patch.png" alt="Max Patch" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><category term="electronic" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Duration: 8 minutes Written for and premiered by David Mercedes Awards and festival appearances: Midwest Composers Symposium, Indiana University, 2019 Program note: Shadow of Sky is inspired by the ancient Chinese song Sky-shading Apricot Blossoms (杏花天影), composed by Jiang Kui in 1187 AD. The piece is built on the first four notes of the original melody, which form a quasi-symmetrical structure. This symmetry serves as a foundation for the piece and recurs throughout its pitch content, rhythmic patterns, and overall form. The tuba, used here as both a melodic and textural voice, employs extended techniques such as exhaling, singing, whispering, and whistling through the instrument to evoke the fragility and depth of an ancient song. These acoustic gestures are captured and transformed in real time through a custom Max/MSP patch, which processes the live input using effects such as granulation, delay, reverb, spatialization, and harmonic layering. Triggering and modulation of the effects are controlled via keyboard input, allowing the performer to interact with and shape the electronics throughout the piece. This integration of live processing and acoustic expression creates a fluid, immersive sound world where tradition and technology intertwine.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wave</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2019/11/01/Wave.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wave" /><published>2019-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2019/11/01/Wave</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2019/11/01/Wave.html"><![CDATA[<ul class="piece-info-list">
  <li>
    For piccolo, 3 flutes, 2 oboes, clarinet in Eb, 3 clarinets in Bb, bass clarinet in Bb, 2 bassoons, contra bassoon, soprano saxophone, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, 3 trumpets in C, 4 horns in F, 2 tenor trombones, bass trombone, tuba, timpani, 3 percussion.
  </li>
  <li>
    Duration: 7 minutes 30 seconds
  </li>
  <li>
    Awards and festival appearances:
    <div class="piece-info-items">
      Alex Shapiro Prize, IAWM Search for New Music, 2020
      <br />
      Midwest Composers Symposium, Indiana University, 2019
    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    Program note: 
    <div class="program-notes">
      This piece is inspired by the wave movement of water ripples. Water waves are a mixture of longitudinal and transverse waves. They have various shapes, directions and dimensions. In this piece, I try to present an auditory illustration of three wave movements and effects, from formation until it fades. In the first section, the wave forms, at a single point, and starts to disperse and expand to the surrounding area. In the second section, we can see the vertical movements the wave causes in the water, rising from a low point gradually to a high point and then cycling back. In the final section, after a long time propagating, the energy of water ripples decreases and we can barely see the wave, but it is still going and moving towards a further place.
    </div>
  </li>
</ul>

<div><iframe class="extensions extensions--audio" width="100%" height="166" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/713967409&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay">
</iframe></div>]]></content><author><name>Wenxin Li</name></author><category term="orchestra" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For piccolo, 3 flutes, 2 oboes, clarinet in Eb, 3 clarinets in Bb, bass clarinet in Bb, 2 bassoons, contra bassoon, soprano saxophone, alto saxophone, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, 3 trumpets in C, 4 horns in F, 2 tenor trombones, bass trombone, tuba, timpani, 3 percussion. Duration: 7 minutes 30 seconds Awards and festival appearances: Alex Shapiro Prize, IAWM Search for New Music, 2020 Midwest Composers Symposium, Indiana University, 2019 Program note: This piece is inspired by the wave movement of water ripples. Water waves are a mixture of longitudinal and transverse waves. They have various shapes, directions and dimensions. In this piece, I try to present an auditory illustration of three wave movements and effects, from formation until it fades. In the first section, the wave forms, at a single point, and starts to disperse and expand to the surrounding area. In the second section, we can see the vertical movements the wave causes in the water, rising from a low point gradually to a high point and then cycling back. In the final section, after a long time propagating, the energy of water ripples decreases and we can barely see the wave, but it is still going and moving towards a further place.]]></summary></entry></feed>